<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Momentary Revelations</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Momentary Revelations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ari Akerstein 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Outside-in or inside-out?</title>
      <link>/posts/in-the-mix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/in-the-mix/</guid>
      <description>Anxiety is increased when I’m outside the mix. When I jump into the churning pot of mess I’m really happy. That’s because I’m focused on the problem and struggles at hand, not on the judgments of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sublime Moments</title>
      <link>/posts/logic-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/logic-magic/</guid>
      <description>Today I reviewed my year. I stared at the sheet of paper - a ledger weighing the good and the bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality before quality</title>
      <link>/posts/quality-before-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/quality-before-quality/</guid>
      <description>We often think of quality as embedded within a product. Does the product have the capabilities and craftsmanship I would expect?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Loops</title>
      <link>/posts/open-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/open-loops/</guid>
      <description>I pass over a graveyard. If I had to guess I would say the overwhelming majority of bones beneath the stones had unfinished business - open loops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aperture</title>
      <link>/posts/aperture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/aperture/</guid>
      <description>Nature opens her aperture through the consciousness of humans. We are nature, instantiated. The peril is not realizing the window of opportunity that exists for those of us blessed to live outside the survival envelope (in which we spend most of our time on survival-related activities).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastery Over Ego</title>
      <link>/posts/mastery-over-ego/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mastery-over-ego/</guid>
      <description>Mastery over ego
Internal interest and direction came from somewhere. If you trace it back ask youself if this came from others or from yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable Us To Pull</title>
      <link>/posts/enable-us-to-pull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/enable-us-to-pull/</guid>
      <description>This is what a product manager (any great leader) must do. This is a deceptively simple phrase but there a lot packed in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flavors Of Exhaustion</title>
      <link>/posts/flavors-of-exhaustion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/flavors-of-exhaustion/</guid>
      <description>There are several flavors of exhaustion. Here’s the taxonomy.
Exhaustion by going shallow This is my enemy. This is what I’ve been doing the past few days as I onboard at a new company (oh, I’m now at Facebook!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Less</title>
      <link>/posts/do-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/do-less/</guid>
      <description>We flew back from Boston a few days ago. I’ve encountered my share of turbulence on planes but this was the worst I had ever experienced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lua Turns 3 years old</title>
      <link>/posts/lua-turns-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lua-turns-3/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Lua turned 3 years old. She helped me get through my dark days. She still does. And her ability to navigate people (already!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The space between sets</title>
      <link>/posts/the-space-between-sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-space-between-sets/</guid>
      <description>If you asked me as a teenager I would have told you the payoff of workouts was in the primal aspects of the activity, the immediate feelings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factory Floor</title>
      <link>/posts/factory-floor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/factory-floor/</guid>
      <description>The cursor pulses hot green against the black terminal. A few quick taps execute the script. I watch the simulation unfold on the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 21:37:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>I use this space to share updates on Product management practice, essays and general observations. Last year I battled a blood cancer cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Grandma</title>
      <link>/posts/goodbye-grandma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/goodbye-grandma/</guid>
      <description>On the way to seeing her I jotted down the memories, talking point bullets in my notebook: the warm feeling from sitting on the carpet as a kid, the smell of spaghetti and meatballs permeating the air on a random weeknight; coming over for breakfast across the driveway for Kasha; etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA folding forces - bioinformatics journal club presentation</title>
      <link>/posts/bioinformatics-investigating-the-forces-involved-in-dna-folding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bioinformatics-investigating-the-forces-involved-in-dna-folding/</guid>
      <description>Notes from a journal club presentation I gave to the Mathematics, Chemistry and Molecular Biology faculty in 2007. This was an elegant study, called on the effect of Force on Mononucleosomal Dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotating the Drosophila Genome</title>
      <link>/posts/bioinformatics-annotating-drosophila-genome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bioinformatics-annotating-drosophila-genome/</guid>
      <description>A Bioinformatics Study &amp;amp; ReportA paper I wrote for a bioinformatics class several years ago in which I annotated part of the Drosophila Erecta genome (Fosmid 14) as part of a concerted effort to annotate the entire genome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2009 Boston Marathon Race Report</title>
      <link>/posts/goboston-marathon-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/goboston-marathon-2009/</guid>
      <description>The day begins at 4:30. I must have eaten more than I can remember the previous night. I cooked up a vat of pasta, garlic bread and salad for a few folks including some fellow K-star runners.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
